MUHAMMAD ADEL DAABOUL

Address: Manchester, United Kingdom, M11

Place of birth: United Kingdom

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/m-d-027032228 Mobile: 07407 256-691

SUMMARY

Full Stack Developer with previous work experience in Auditing and Finance. Known throughout the 7 years of experience to be meticulous, resilient and innovative. Currently attending a Full-Stack Web Development Bootcamp with a portfolio of work available on GitHub which showcases how awesome my web development skills have become in a span of 7 months.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Frameworks: React.js, Node.js, Express.js, Bootstrap and Bulma.

Programming Languages: JavaScript (ES6) and R.

Technologies: MongoDB, MySQL, GraphQL, RESTful API's, Material UI, Handlebars.js,

Cloudinary, Redux, jQuery, Git, GitHub, HTML and CSS.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Apr 2022 **Portfolio:** React.js, JavaScript, GitHub API, Formspree.

My portfolio built with React.js.

Live link: https://moedaaboul.github.io

GitHub: https://github.com/moedaaboul/moedaaboul.github.io

Feb 2022 - Mar 2022 Legogram - Technologies: JavaScript, Node.js, Express.js, Sequelize ORM, MySQL,

Cloudinary, Heroku, and Bulma.

A full-stack social network for Lego creators built with Node.is, Sequelize and Handlebars.is.

Live link: https://legogram.herokuapp.com

GitHub: https://github.com/moedaaboul/legogram

Feb 2022 Tech Blog - Technologies: JavaScript, Node.js, Express.js,

Sequelize ORM, MySQL, Heroku, and Bulma.

A CMS-style blog site that follows the MVC paradigm. Live link: https://mdaaboul-tech-blog.herokuapp.com GitHub: https://github.com/moedaaboul/tech-blog

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Sep 2020 – Nov 2021 **Foundation Home Loans** Berkshire, RG12 1WA

Portfolio: https://moedaaboul.github.io GitHub: https://github.com/moedaaboul

Email: muhammad.daaboul1989@gmail.com

Finance Manager - Financial Reporting (worked remotely from home in Manchester)

- Built effective visualisations and dashboards using ggplot2 and Microsoft Excel.
- Rebuilt processes using R to improve the accuracy and efficiency of certain processes related to the preparation of financial statements.
- · Accomplished reviews of fair value and cash flow hedge accounting journals and liaised with third party experts and internal department heads to oversee and manage the hedge accounting process.
- Completed critical reviews of financial models in Excel to help ease the cash flow forecasting process in relation to several processes.
- Liaised with external auditors on audit queries in relation to critical areas of the audit process.
- Resolved issues related to complex financial models in relation to EIR, IFRS 9 and communicated findings directly to the Head of Financial Reporting and the CFO.
- Trusted by the Head of Financial Reporting and CFO to accomplish multiple critical projects.
- Directed 3 junior team members throughout various financial reporting and control functions. Encouraged team members and acknowledged their efforts when working under strict deadlines.

Jan 2019 – Jul 2020 KPMG UK Manchester, M2 3AE

Assistant Manager – Financial Services

- Handled inquiries with Department Heads, and Team leaders throughout the audits of multiple engagements.
- Executed annual financial statements reviews, annual reports and group reporting information with supporting documentation under various accounting standards (i.e. IFRS, US GAAP, FRS 101, and FRS 102)
- Facilitated audit close meetings with multiple clients and contributed to the team discussion on various points.
- Devised procedures in relation to complex audit transactions surrounding debt sale processes for credit businesses, which involved forward flows, insolvency sales and spot sales. Additionally, developed an understanding of the processes surrounding the opposite side of the transactions through leading the audit of debt purchasers.
- Trained and coached a group of 3-5 junior team members and communicated results directly to Senior Management.

Mar 2017 – Jun 2018

PricewaterhouseCoopers

Dubai, UAE

Acting Manager - External Audit (Promoted to an acting Manager role in five months)

- Inspired and mentored Senior Associates and conveyed engagement progress to Directors and Partners.
- Participated in discussions with high-profile clients in clearance meetings and also contributed to internal discussions with PwC's Department Head's such as Risk & Quality, Capital Markets and accounting advisory services (CMAAS), and Methodology to resolve pertinent accounting, auditing, and legal issues.
- Managed 7 teams, a portfolio of clients, and monitored budgets to ensure that WIP is within budget and billed on time.
- Increased business prospects, by analysing the financial position and performance of prospective clients, writing proposals and promoting the business.

Aug 2015 – Mar 2017 KPMG Channel Islands Limited

Channel Islands, GY1 1WR

Assistant Manager - External Audit

- Undertook the field in-charge role on large and complex engagements.
- Collaborated on the annual review of the Fiduciary Services sector in Guernsey with the Advisory team and completed a deliverable to the Guernsey Financial Services Commission (GFSC).
- Mentored 2-3 junior members of the team and performed critical reviews of their work papers.
- Succeeded in addressing Managers' and Partners' queries and contributed to multiple control improvement findings to stakeholders.

EDUCATION

Oct 2021 – May 2022

University of Manchester Coding Bootcamp Certificate

Manchester, UK

Full Stack Web Development

Tech stack includes: JavaScript, React.js, Node.js, Express.js, RESTful API's, GraphQL,

MongoDB, MySQL, Redux, Git, HTML and CSS.

Certified Public Accountant

NH, USA

American Institute of Certified Public Accountants

American University of Beirut

Beirut, Lebanon

Bachelor of Business Administration: Accounting (GPA: 81.26)